Finding Aid for Frank Murphy Papers, 1908-1949
Bentley Historical Library
Frank Murphy papers
1908-1949
Bentley Historical Library
Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949
86734 Aa 2, Ac,UAl
166 microfilms
24 linear feet (in 28 boxes)
7 oversize volumes
2 oversize folders
474 MB
Michigan born lawyer, judge, politician and diplomat, served as Detroit Recorder's Court Judge, Mayor of Detroit, Governor General of the Philippines, Governor of Michigan, U. S. Attorney General and U.S. Supreme Court Justice. Papers include extensive correspondence, subject files, Supreme court case files, scrapbooks, photographs and other material.
The Frank Murphy collection came to the library from a variety of sources, but primarily from the estate of his brother George Murphy. The bulk of the collection came to the library in 1961 and 1965. Smaller accessions of materials came throughout the 1960s. The donor number for the collection is 3074.
The collection is open for research. User's must sign a Murphy Papers Contract stipulating certain conditions for use. Copies of the contract are available from the Bentley Library reference archivist. For the portions of the collection which have been microfilmed, the original documents are closed, researchers must use the microfilm edition. The microfilm edition is available through inter-library loan.
The collection contains audio tapes from which digital copies have been made. Source tapes are for staff use only. Audio files are only available in the Bentley Historical Library reading room on designated Bentley Library computers.
Digitization: The Library has undertaken the digitization of a number of sound recordings within this collection. The resulting audio files are available for playback only in the Bentley Library Reading Room. Links to item images and additional information are available within this finding aid. Original sound recordings are only available for staff use.
The career of Frank Murphy was distinguished by the varied scope of his public service. For three decades, he was Michigan's best-known public servant, a consummate politician, known and respected by thousands. Murphy was born April 13, 1890 in Sand Beach (later Harbor Beach), Michigan. He graduated from the University of Michigan Law School in 1914, served in the infantry during World War I, and upon his discharge received appointment as first assistant United States attorney for the Eastern District of Michigan.
Although a holder of high political office, Murphy kept coming back to the law. In 1923, he was elected Detroit Recorder's Court judge. Here, he won national attention with his one-man grand jury probe into various departments and as presiding judge in the famous Sweet trial. In 1930, following the removal by recall of Charles W. Bowles, Murphy was elected mayor of the city of Detroit. He was reelected in 1931 and served until May 1933. As mayor during the heart of the depression, Murphy won high marks for his efforts to deal with the devastation caused by widespread unemployment.
A staunch supporter of Franklin Roosevelt in his presidential campaign of 1932, Murphy was rewarded with appointment as governor-general of the Philippines. He served in this position until the inauguration of the Philippine Commonwealth in November 1935 at which time he became the United States high commissioner. At President Roosevelt's urging, he returned to the United States in 1936 to run for governor of Michigan. In that Democratic year, Murphy won handily. His term as governor was marked by the Flint sit-down strike and his efforts to bring New Deal reforms to Michigan government.
In 1939, Roosevelt appointed Murphy to serve as attorney general of the United States. He distinguished himself as a crusader against crime and corruption. The attorney general was primarily responsible for establishing a civil liberties unit within the Justice Department. Murphy served as head of the Justice Department until January 1940 when he was appointed to the U.S. Supreme Court. For nine years, often in the role of a dissenter, Murphy championed the cause of civil liberties.
Following difficulties with his heart, Frank Murphy died July 19, 1949.
Series I: Correspondence, 1908-1949. - Rolls 1-91 Index to correspondence, Boxes 100-103
Series II: Other Papers, 1890-1949. - Rolls 91-121
Pre-Detroit Mayoralty, 1890-1929. - Rolls 91-97
Mayor of Detroit, 1930-1933. Rolls 97-98
P.I. Governor General/High Commissioner, 1933-1936. - Rolls 98-108
Governor of Michigan, 1936-1938. - Rolls 108-111
U.S. Attorney General, 1939-1940. - Rolls 111-116
U.S. Supreme Court Justice, 1940-1949. - Rolls 117-120
Series III: Supreme Court Case Files. - Rolls 121-141; Boxes 104-105
Series IV: Speech File. - Rolls 141-146
Series V: Speech Material.
Frank Murphy related. - Rolls 146-147
Non-Frank Murphy. - Boxes 78-83
Series VI: Miscellaneous Material - Rolls 147-154; Boxes 84-85, 87-94
Personal correspondence
Appointment calendars
Printed material
Series VII: Visual Materials - Boxes 95-98; oversize folders
Series VIII: Newsclippings/Scrapbooks - Rolls 155-165
Finding Aid - Roll 166
The Frank Murphy Collection documents in detail the life and career of one of Michigan's most distinguished public servants. Through correspondence, subject files, scrapbooks, visual materials, and other documentation, the collection traces Murphy's life from his years as Detroit judge, later Mayor, to his service in the Philippines, his tenure as governor, his stint as U.S. Attorney General, and culminating in his final years as U.S. Supreme Court Justice.
The Frank Murphy Collection consists of eight series: Correspondence, Other Papers, Supreme Court Case Files, Speech File, Speech Material, Miscellaneous, Visual Material, and Newsclippings/Scrapbooks.
Civil service.; Courts -- Michigan.; Detroit (Mich.); Judges -- United States.; Labor -- Michigan.; Michigan -- Politics and government -- 1922-1928.; Michigan -- Politics and government -- 1929-1938.; Philippines -- History -- 1898-1946.; Strikes and lockouts -- Michigan.; United States -- Foreign relations -- Philippines.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1929-1933.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1933-1945.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1945-1953.; General Motors Corporation Sit-Down Strike, 1936-1937.; Governors -- Michigan.; Sit-down strikes -- Michigan -- Flint.; Afro-Americans -- Work.; Building dedications.; Capitols -- Michigan -- Lansing.; Christmas cards.; Clothing and dress -- 1921-1930.; Clothing and dress -- 1931-1940.; Crowds.; Demonstrations.; Detroit (Mich.); Detroit (Mich.) -- Mayors.; Detroit (Mich.) -- Newspaper industry.; Dentistry -- Michigan.; Drawings.; Dwellings -- Michigan -- Harbor Beach.; Diseases.; Europe.; Funeral rites and ceremonies.; Galleries and museums -- Michigan -- Harbor Beach.; Governors -- Michigan.; Governors -- Philippines.; Harbor Beach (Mich.); Harbor Beach (Mich.) -- Dwellings.; Harbor Beach (Mich.) -- Galleries and museums.; Horseback riding.; Interiors.; Judges -- United States.; Hospitals -- Philippines.; Laborers.; Lying in state.; Mayors -- Michigan -- Detroit.; Michigan -- Capitols.; Military camps.; Military training.; Motion pictures.; Newspaper carriers.; Newspaper industry -- Michigan -- Detroit.; Oaths.; Offices.; Painting.; Parades and processions.; Philippines -- History -- 1898-1946.; Philippines -- War damage.; Political elections -- 1936.; Politics and government -- 1929-1938.; Politics and government -- 1939-1945.; Politics and government -- 1946-1960.; Public speaking.; Radio broadcasting -- Michigan -- Detroit.; Recreation.; Religious services.; Strikes.; Tanks (Military science); Toasting.; Voting.; War casualties.; War damage -- Philippines.; Warships.; Women.; Cartoons.; Photographs.; Postcards.; Posters.; Scrapbooks.; Sound recordings.; Videotapes.; Democratic Party (Mich.); Detroit (Mich.). Mayor.; Detroit (Mich.). Recorder's Court.; Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.; United States. Attorney General.; United States. Supreme Court.; American Legion.; City Hall (Detroit, Mich.); Michigan. Legislature.; Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.; Murphy family.; Philippine War Relief of the United States.; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945.; United States. Supreme Court.; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.; Williams, G. Mennen, 1911-1988.; Acheson, Dean, 1893-1971.; Andrews, Roger, 1874-; Arnold, Thurman Wesley, 1891-1969.; Ashurst, Henry Fountain, 1874-1962.; Austin, Warren Robinson, 1877-1963.; Baker, Newton Diehl, 1871-1937.; Barkley, Alben William, 1877-1956.; Barnes, Russell.; Barrymore, Ethel, 1879-1959.; Bates, Henry Moore, 1869-1949.; Bennett, Harry Herbert, 1892-1979.; Biddle, Nicholas, 1893-; Bingay, Malcolm, 1884-1953.; Black, Hugo LaFayette, 1886-1971.; Borah, William Edgar, 1865-1940.; Brandeis, Louis Dembitz, 1856-1941.; Browder, Earl, 1891-1973.; Brown, Prentiss M. (Prentiss Marsh), 1889-1973.; Bumgardner, Eleanor M. (Eleanor Margaret); Burton, Harold H. (Harold Hitz), 1888-1964.; Butler, Pierce.; Byrnes, James Francis, 1879-1972.; Chandler, Happy, 1898-1991.; Chrysler, Walter Percy, 1875-1940.; Clark, Champ, 1850-1921.; Clark, Tom C. (Tom Campbell), 1899-1977.; Coblentz, Edmond D.; Cohen, Benjamin V.; Comstock, William Alfred, 1877-1949.; Cooley, Mortimer E. (Mortimer Elwyn), 1855-1944.; Corcoran, Thomas Gardiner, 1900-; Coughlin, Charles E. (Charles Edward), 1891-1979.; Couzens, James, 1872-1936.; Creighton, Joseph.; Crittenberg, Willis.; Cromwell, James Henry Roberts.; Cropley, Charles Elmore.; Cummings, Homer S.; Curley, James M.; Daniels, Josephus, 1862-1948.; Davies, Joseph Edward.; De Kruif, Paul, 1890-1971.; Dern, George Henry, 1872-1936.; De Valera, Eamonn, 1882-1975.; Dever, Paul A. (Paul Andrew), 1903-1958.; Dewey, Thomas E. (Thomas Edmund), 1902-1971.; Dickinson, Luren Dudley, 1859-1943.; Dingell, John D. (John David), 1894-1955.; Donnelly, Joseph P.; Douglas, William O. (William Orville), 1898-1980.; Early, Stephen.; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969.; Farley, James A. (James Aloysius), 1888-1976.; Fellers, Bonner Frank, 1896-1973.; Fitzgerald, Frank Dwight, 1885-1939.; Ford, Edsel, 1893-1943.; Ford, Henry, 1863-1947.; Foy, Byron Cecil, 1893-1970.; Frankfurter, Felix, 1882-1965.; Fuller, Glenn.; Gallagher, Michael James, 1866-1937.; Garner, John Nance, 1868-1967.; Giannini, Amadeo Peter, 1870-1949.; Green, William, 1870-1952.; Gressman, Eugene, 1917-2010.; Haber, William, 1899-1988.; Hannah, John A., 1902-1991.; Hawes, Harry B.; Hayden, Joseph Ralston, 1887-1945.; Hays, Arthur Garfield, 1881-1954.; Hearst, William Randolph, 1863-1951.; Hill, Norman Hingston, 1887-1971.; Hillman, Sidney, 1887-1946.; Hoffman, Clare Eugene, 1875-1967.; Hoover, J. Edgar (John Edgar), 1895-1972.; Hopkins, Harry L. (Harry Lloyd), 1890-1946.; Hotzoff, Alexander.; Howe, Louis McHenry, 1871-1936.; Hughes, Charles Evans, 1862-1948.; Hull, Cordell, 1871-1955.; Hurley, Patrick J. (Patrick Jay), 1883-1963.; Ickes, Harold L. (Harold LeClair), 1874-1952.; Jackson, Robert Houghwout, 1892-1954.; Jones, Jesse H. (Jesse Holman), 1874-1956.; Kemp, Edward Gearing, 1887-1962.; Kennedy, Joseph P. (Joseph Patrick), 1888-1969.; Knox, Frank, 1874-1944.; Knudsen, William S., 1879-1948.; Krock, Arthur, 1886-1974.; LaFollette, Philip Fox, 1897-1965.; La Follette, Robert M. (Robert Marion), 1855-1925.; La Guardia, Fiorello H. (Fiorello Henry), 1882-1947.; LeHand, Margaret.; Lehman, Herbert H. (Herbert Henry), 1878-1963.; Lewis, James H.; Lewis, John Llewellyn, 1880-1969.; Lincoln, Esther, 1879-1961.; Lindley, Ernest Kidder, 1899-; Littell, Norman M.; Lodge, Henry Cabot, Jr., 1902-1985.; Long, Breckinridge, 1881-1958.; Luce, Clare Boothe, 1903-1987.; McAdoo, William Gibbs, 1863-1941.; MacArthur, Douglas, 1880-1964.; MacDonald, Kenneth.; McEvoy, Joseph P.; McGrath, J. Howard (James Howard), 1903-1966.; McGuire, Matthew F., 1921-; McKay, Frank, 1883-1965.; McKellar, Kenneth Douglas, 1869-1957.; McMahon, Brien, 1903-1952.; McNutt, Paul Vories, 1891-1955.; McReynolds, James C.; Malcolm, George A. (George Arthur), 1881-1961.; Maloney, Francis.; Manning, John C. (John Charles), 1893-1967.; Marshall, George C. (George Catlett), 1880-1959.; Marshall, S. L. A. (Samuel Lyman Atwood), 1900-1977.; Marshall, Thurgood, 1908-1993.; Martel, Frank Xavier, 1888-; Mershon, Elsie.; Minton, Sherman.; Moehlman, Arthur B. (Arthur Bernard), 1889-1952.; Moley, Raymond L., 1886-; Montague, Gilbert H.; Moody, Blair, 1902-1954.; Mooney, Edward, Archbishop, 1882-1958.; Moore, James W.; Morgenthau, Henry, 1856-1946.; Murphy, George, 1897-1961.; Murphy, William F.; Murray, Philip, 1886-1952.; Norris, George W. (George William), 1861-1944.; Nowicki, Leo J., 1904-; O'Brien, John J.; Olander, Oscar G. (Oscar Gustaf), 1899-1963.; Olson, Culbert L. (Culbert Levy), 1876-1962.; Osborn, Chase S. (Chase Salmon), 1860-; Osmeña, Sergio, 1878-1961.; Parker, Francis LeJau, 1873-1966.; Patterson, Robert Porter, 1891-1952.; Patton, George S. (George Smith), 1885-1945.; Pearson, Drew, 1897-1969.; Pepper, Claude, 1900-1989.; Perkins, Frances, 1882-1965.; Picard, Frank A., 1889-1963.; Pinchot, Gifford, 1865-1946.; Pittman, Key, 1872-1940.; Pollock, James K. (James Kerr), 1898-1968.; Porter, Russell B.; Pressman, Lee.; Quirino, Elpidio, 1890-1956.; Rabaut, Louis Charles, 1886-1961.; Reed, Stanley F.; Roberts, Owen J. (Owen Josephus), 1875-1955.; Rogge, O. John (Oetje John), 1903-1981.; Romulo, Carlos P. (Carlos Peña), 1899-1985.; Roosevelt, Dorothy Kemp, 1899-1985.; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962.; Roosevelt, Elliott, 1910-1990.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945.; Roosevelt, G. Hall.; Roosevelt, James, 1907-1991.; Roper, Daniel C.; Roxas, Manuel.; Ruthven, Alexander Grant, 1882-1971.; Rutledge, Wiley Blount, 1894-1949.; Sadowski, George Gregory, 1903-1961.; Sandburg, Carl, 1878-1967.; Sayre, Francis Bowes, 1885-1972.; Schlesinger, Arthur Meier, 1888-1965.; Schlesinger, Arthur M., Jr. (Arthur Meier), 1917-2007.; Shafroth, Morrison.; Sheen, Fulton J. (Fulton John), 1895-1979.; Shields, Edmund Claude, 1871-1947.; Sigler, Kim, 1894-; Sloan, Alfred P. (Alfred Pritchard), 1875-1966.; Smathers, William H.; Smith, Alfred Emanuel, 1873-1944.; Snyder, John W. (John Wesley), 1895-1985.; Spellman, Francis, 1889-1967.; Stark, Lloyd C.; Starr, Raymond Wesley, 1888-1968.; Stason, E. Blythe (Edwin Blythe), 1891-1972.; Stettinius, Edward R. (Edward Reilly), 1900-1949.; Stidger, William L. (William LeRoy), 1886-; Stimson, Henry L. (Henry Lewis), 1867-1950.; Stone, Harlan Fiske, 1872-1946.; Straus, Nathan.; Summers, Halton W.; Swope, Herbert Bayard, 1882-1958.; Thomas, Norman, 1884-1968.; Tobin, Daniel J.; Tobin, Maurice Joseph, 1901-; Topping, Daniel J.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972.; Tydings, Millard E.; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.; Vanderbilt, Neil.; Van Wagoner, Murray Delos, 1898-; Vinson, Fred M., 1890-1953.; Wallace, Henry Agard, 1888-1965.; Wheeler, Burton K. (Burton Kendall), 1882-1975.; White, Walter Francis, 1893-1955.; White, William Allen, 1868-1944.; Williams, G. Mennen, 1911-1988.; Willkie, Wendell L. (Wendell Lewis), 1892-1944.; Winchell, Walter, 1897-1972.; Yost, Fielding Harris, 1871-1946.; Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.; United States. Dept. of Justice.
- Correspondence, 1908-1949
  Correspondence, 1908-1949 (Microfilm rolls 1-91, Manuscript boxes 1-47). The series has been arranged chronologically, with undated letters placed at the end of the relevant month, year, or decade, depending on which is apparent, or at the very end of the series, if no date is apparent. Other undated letters have been categorized by periods of Murphy's life (e.g., Detroit period, gubernatorial period, etc.) and placed at the end of the period. The Bentley Historical Library has a large (but not complete) name index to the incoming correspondence files (boxes 100-103, not microfilmed).
  - Index to correspondence, A-Flynn (Box 100)
  - Index to correspondence, Fo-Lytle (Box 101)
  - Index to correspondence, M-Vestal (Box 102)
  - Index to correspondence, Vi-Z and an additional index to correspondence that was filed separately (Box 103)
  - 1908-April 2, 1923 (Reel 1)
  - April 3, 1923-December 1924 (Reel 2)
  - January 1925-July 1927 (Reel 3)
  - August 1927-March 28, 1930 (Reel 4)
  - April 1930-September 10, 1930 (Reel 5)
  - September 11, 1930-September 22, 1930 (Reel 6)
  - September 22, 1930-October 30, 1930 (Reel 7)
  - November 1, 1930-August 14, 1931 (Reel 8)
  - August 15, 1931-October 21, 1931 (Reel 9)
  - October 22, 1931-December 31, 1931 (Reel 10)
  - Undated 1931-April 9 1933 (Reel 11)
  - April 10, 1933-May 7, 1933 (Reel 12)
  - May 8, 1933-July 19, 1933 (Reel 13)
  - July 20, 1933-October 15, 1933 (Reel 14)
  - October 16, 1933-January 15, 1934 (Reel 15)
  - January 16, 1934-April 20, 1934 (Reel 16)
  - April 21, 1934-August 31, 1934 (Reel 17)
  - September 1-November 12, 1934 (Reel 18)
  - November 13, 1934-January 21, 1935 (Reel 19)
  - January 22-March 24, 1935 (Reel 20)
  - March 25-May 14, 1935 (Reel 21)
  - May 15-July 26, 1935 (Reel 22)
  - July 27-September 30, 1935 (Reel 23)
  - October 1-November 14, 1935 (Reel 24)
  - November 15-Undated, 1935 (Reel 25)
  - January 1-February 13, 1936 (Reel 26)
  - February 14-April 4, 1936 (Reel 27)
  - April 5-June 30, 1936 (Reel 28)
  - July 1-September 30, 1936 (Reel 29)
  - October 1-November 26, 1936 (Reel 30)
  - November 27, 1936-January 15, 1937 (Reel 31)
  - January 16-February 8, 1937 (Reel 32)
  - February 9-February 25, 1937 (Reel 33)
  - February 26-April 8, 1937 (Reel 34)
  - April 9-June 14, 1937 (Reel 35)
  - June 15-September 9, 1937 (Reel 36)
  - September 10-November 30, 1937 (Reel 37)
  - December 1, 1937-January 22, 1938 (Reel 38)
  - January 23-April 6, 1938 (Reel 39)
  - April 7-May 31, 1938 (Reel 40)
  - June 1-July 25, 1938 (Reel 41)
  - July 26-September 20, 1938 (Reel 42)
  - September 21-November 9, 1938 (Reel 43)
  - November 10-December 6, 1938 (Reel 44)
  - December 7-Undated, 1938 (Reel 45)
  - Undated, Gubernatorial period (Reel 45)
  - January 1-8, 1939 (Reel 46)
  - January 9-20, 1939 (Reel 47)
  - January 21-February 8, 1939 (Reel 48)
  - February 9-March 6, 1939 (Reel 49)
  - March 7-29, 1939 (Reel 50)
  - March 30-April 21, 1939 (Reel 51)
  - April 22-May 16, 1939 (Reel 52)
  - May 17-June 11, 1939 (Reel 53)
  - June 12-July 5, 1939 (Reel 54)
  - July 6-Undated, July 1939 (Reel 55)
  - August 1-September 10, 1939 (Reel 56)
  - September 11-October 15, 1939 (Reel 57)
  - October 16-November 13, 1939 (Reel 58)
  - November 14-December 13, 1939 (Reel 59)
  - December 14, 1939-January 3, 1940 (Reel 60)
  - January 4-12, 1940 (Reel 61)
  - Undated (Reel 62)
    (Justice Dept. period)
  - January 13-27, 1940 (Reel 62)
  - January 28-February 26, 1940 (Reel 63)
  - February 27-April 15, 1940 (Reel 64)
  - April 16-June 30, 1940 (Reel 65)
  - July 1-November 6, 1940 (Reel 66)
  - November 7, 1940-January 12, 1941 (Reel 67)
  - January 13-April 5, 1941 (Reel 68)
  - April 6-Undated, July 1941 (Reel 69)
  - August 1-November 16, 1941 (Reel 70)
  - November 17, 1941-January 13, 1942 (Reel 71)
  - January 14-March 31, 1942 (Reel 72)
  - April 1-June 30, 1942 (Reel 73)
  - July 1-November 11, 1942 (Reel 74)
  - November 12, 1942-February 6, 1943 (Reel 75)
  - February 7-May 15, 1943 (Reel 76)
  - May 16-October 10, 1943 (Reel 77)
  - October 11, 1943-February 15, 1944 (Reel 78)
  - February 16-June 12, 1944 (Reel 79)
  - June 13-December 13, 1944 (Reel 80)
  - December 14, 1944-March 14, 1945 (Reel 81)
  - March 15-August 15, 1945 (Reel 82)
  - August 16, 1945-January 13, 1946 (Reel 83)
  - January 14-June 7, 1946 (Reel 84)
  - June 8-December 10, 1946 (Reel 85)
  - December 11, 1946-May 5, 1947 (Reel 86)
  - May 6-November 8, 1947 (Reel 87)
  - November 9, 1947-May 10, 1948 (Reel 88)
  - May 11, 1948-January 24, 1949 (Reel 89)
  - January 25-November 1949 (Reel 90)
  - December 1949 (Reel 91)
  - Undated, 1940s (Reel 91)
  - Undated (Reel 91)
    (Supreme Court period)
  - Undated (Reel 91)
- Papers, 1890-1949
  (arranged broadly by the different phases of FM's career)
  Papers, 1890-1949 (Rolls 91-121, Boxes 48-62). The series, chronologically arranged, consists of non-correspondence materials covering the various phases in Frank Murphy's career. Files include Detroit Recorder's Court papers, official records collected while he was governor-general of the Philippine Islands, gubernatorial files, and attorney general files (including memoranda within the Department of Justice). There is a separate series of Murphy's Supreme Court files. Like correspondence, undated papers come at the end of their known sequence.
  - Pre-Detroit mayoralty period, 1890-1929
    - Baptismal certificate (Reel 91)
    - Student paper entitled "Politics and the Laborer", undated (Reel 91)
    - Transcripts of University of Michigan undergraduate and law school grades (Reel 91)
    - University of Michigan Law School materials (Reel 91)
    - University of Michigan student miscellanea (Reel 91)
    - Diaries and daybooks, pre-1920 (Reel 91)
    - Military and Officers Reserve Corps papers
      - 1917-1922 (Reel 91)
      - 1923-1942, undated (Reel 92)
    - Papers, pre-1920; 1920-1922 (Reel 92)
    - University of Detroit and Detroit College of Law class materials, 1923-1924 (Reel 92)
    - Papers concerning arbitration between city of Detroit and the Detroit City Gas Co., 1923-1924 (Reel 92)
    - Recorder's Court papers, 1919-April 1926 (Reel 92)
    - Recorder's Court papers, May 1926 (Reel 92)
      (Ossian Sweet case)
    - Recorder's Court papers, May 1926-January 1927 (Reel 92)
    - Recorder's Court papers, February-December 1927; 1927 undated (Reel 93)
    - Papers concerning capital punishment, 1927 (Reel 93)
    - Papers concerning National Conference on the Reduction of Crime, National Crime Commission, November 2-3, 1927 (Reel 93)
    - Papers concerning King Felton, Man of Mystery, Ovid, Michigan, 1923-1927 (Reel 93)
    - Recorder's Court papers, January-April 1928 (Reel 93)
    - Recorder's Court papers (Widening of Bagley Avenue), May-June 1928 (Reel 93)
    - Recorder's Court papers (Dodge Brothers vs. City of Hamtramck), June 1928 (Reel 93)
    - Recorder's Court papers, July 1928-December 1929; 1920s undated (Reel 93)
    - Recorder's Court papers, January-December 1930; 1930 undated (Reel 94)
    - Legal miscellanea 1910s, 1920s (Daisy Binkle case), 1910-1929 (Reel 94)
    - Legal materials, 1920s (Reel 94)
    - Miscellaneous legal case memoranda (Reel 94)
    - Printed legal briefs, 1920s (Reel 94)
    - Papers, 1923-1925 (Reel 94)
    - Papers, 1926-1929; 1920s undated (Reel 95)
    - Miscellaneous writings (not Frank Murphy), 1920s (Reel 95)
    - Papers, 1930 (Reel 95)
    - Ford-Blair Arbitration
      - Papers, 1926-1928; undated (Reel 95)
      - Correspondence re: fees, June 3-19, 1929 (Reel 96)
      - Transcripts of proceedings, March-December 1928 (Reel 96)
      - Progress statements, May and August 1928 (Reel 96)
      - Ford arbitrator statement re:
        - Paint, November 15, 1928 (Reel 97)
        - Paint-steel mill, December 15, 1928 (Reel 97)
        - Somerville contract #755, 1928 (Reel 97)
      - Summary, 1928 (Reel 97)
      - Final award, February 15, 1929 (Reel 97)
    - Woodward Avenue widening
      - Property surveys (Reel 97)
      - Property appraisal appeals, 1929 (Reel 97)
  - Mayor of Detroit, 1930-1933
    - Papers, January-December 1931; 1931 undated (Reel 97)
    - Papers concerning national convention of the American Legion, Detroit, 1931 (Reel 97)
    - Mayor's Appointment Calendar, 1931 (Reel 97)
    - Papers, January-June 1932 (Reel 97)
    - Conference of Mayors of the United States held at Detroit, Michigan, June 1, 1932 (Reel 98)
    - Papers, July 1932-April 1933 (Reel 98)
    - Miscellaneous Mayoralty papers, circa 1932-1933 (Reel 98)